Guide to the Arthur Clarence Walworth Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arthur Clarence Walworth papers
1868-2003
1868-1994
MS 532
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.5
The papers consist of correspondence, research materials, and writings on Woodrow Wilson, Commodore Perry's expedition, and American diplomacy at the end of World War I. Correspondence with biographer Phyllis Levin is included in the papers.
Walworth, Arthur, 1903-2005
Immediate Source of Acquisition
With the exception of one box, the papers were deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1972-1993 and 1999; and were the gift of Ellen R. Ebersole, 1993. Accession 1995-M-091 was deposited by Ellen Ebersole in 1994. Gift of Arthur C. Walworth, 2004.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
Arthur Clarence Walworth, historian and author, was born in Newton, Massachusetts, in 1903. He received a B.A. degree from Yale in 1925. Walworth taught English and modern European history in China and traveled in Japan and Europe. In 1927 he joined the educational department of Houghton Mifflin. Walworth received the Pulitzer Prize in biography in 1958 for his book on Woodrow Wilson. He is the author of School Histories at War, 1938; Black Ships off Japan, 1946; Cape Breton, 1948; The Medomak Way, 1953; Woodrow Wilson, 2 vols., 1958; America's Moment, 1918, 1977; and Wilson and His Peacemakers, 1986. Walworth died on January 10, 2005, in Needham, Massachusetts.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, research materials, and writings on Woodrow Wilson, Commodore Perry's expedition, and American diplomacy at the end of World War I. Correspondence with biographer Phyllis Levin is included in the papers.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
United States -- Foreign relations; United States -- Politics and government; Authors; Axson, Margaret Callaway; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965; Beatty, Julian B.; Beaumont, Maurice; Benham, Edith Wallace; Bingham, Hiram, 1875-1956; Bones, Helen Woodrow; Brahany, Thomas W., 1877-; Brownlow, Louis, 1879-1963; Bryant, Charles L.; Bullitt, William C. (William Christian), 1891-1967; Capps, Edward, 1866-1950; Cecil, Robert, 1913-; Close, Gilbert F., 1881-1952; Clothier, Robert C. (Robert Clarkson), 1885-1970; Cobb, Margaret Ayer; Colby, Edith; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952; Coombe, George W.; Corwin, Edward S. (Edward Samuel), 1878-1963; Crawford, Jack Randall, 1878-; Cummings, Homer S. (Homer Stillé), 1870-1956; Daniels, Jonathan, 1902-1981; Davies, John William, 1873-1955; De Witt, John, 1842-1923; Dunlop, George; Fosdick, Raymond B. (Raymond Blaine), 1883-1972; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; Gamble, Millard; George, Robert H.; Gipson, Lawrence Henry, 1880-1971; Grant, U. S. (Ulysses S.), 1881-1968; Hankey, Maurice Pascal Alers Hankey, Baron, 1877-1963; Harbin, Edith Lester, 1876-1960; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Kahler, Hugh MacNair, 1883-1969; Kellogg, George Dwight, 1873-; Levin, Phyllis Lee; Mantoux, Paul, 1877-1956; Moody, John, 1868-1958; Nicolson, Harold, 1886-1968; Notestein, Wallace, 1878-1969; Perry, Bliss, 1860-1954; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Sweetser, Arthur, 1888-1968; Swem, Charles Lee; Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958; Thompson, Huston; Toynbee, Arnold, 1889-1975; Walworth, Arthur, 1903-2005; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Woolley, Robert Wickliffe, 1871-1958
- Original accession, 0.5; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence and interviews with various people re: Woodrow Wilson
  - Axson, Margaret Callaway
    - Interview: 1 page, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1914, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baruch, Bernard M.
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1948, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: 6 items, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beaty, Julian B., Correspondence: 5 items, 1949-1950, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Beaumont, Maurice
    General note
    See: box 1, folder 35
  - Benham, Edith
    See: Edith Benham Helm
  - Bingham, Hiram, Jr.
    See: box 1, folder 44
  - Bones, Helen Woodrow
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: 46 items, 1914, 1943, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bradford, Edward W.
  - Brahany, Thomas W.
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Notes and News Clipping (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Edward
    See: box 1, folder 29
  - Brownlow, Louis
    - Interview: 3 pages, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1952, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bryant, Charles. L., Correspondence: 2 items, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bullitt, William C., Interview: 4 pages, 1951, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Capps, Prof. Edward, Correspondence: 2 items, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cecil, Lord Robert
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - News Clipping (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charles-Roux, François
  - Close, Gilbert
    - Correspondence: 10 items, 1948-1949, 1951, 1955, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Notes and News Clipping (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clothier, Robert C., Correspondence: 1 item, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cobb, Margaret Ayer (Mrs. Frank), Correspondence: 2 items, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Colby, Edith (Mrs. Everett), Correspondence: 1 item, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Comert, P.
  - Conklin, E. G.
  - Coombe, George, Correspondence: 1 item, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Corwin, Edward S.
  - Crawford, Jack
  - Cummings, Homer
    - Interview: 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: 7 items, 1953, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Daniels, Jonathan
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ms. Pages (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Davies, Joseph E.
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: 3 items, 1954, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ms. Page and Notes (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Davis, John W. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Interview: 1 page, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 4 items, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - De Witt, John
  - Duff, George. M., Correspondence: 1 item, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Duff, William M., Correspondence: 1 item, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dunlop, George
  - Durner, Will
  - Eisenhart, Luther P.
  - Elliott, Margaret Axson, Interview: 1 page, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fosdick, Raymond D.
    - Interview: 1 page, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: 6 items, 1948, 1952, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Pamphlet and Printed Material, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Fosdick, Raymond D.
    See: box 1, folder 23
  - Frankfurter, Felix
    - Interview: 2 pages (and copy), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: 3 items, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gamble, Millard, Interview: 1 page, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - George, Robert H.
    - Interview: 1 page, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: 3 items, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Gérand, André
  - Gipson, Lawrence Henry, Printed Material (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Grant, Ulysses S. 3rd, Interview: 1 page, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hankey, Lord Maurice (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence: 24 items, 1951, 1953-1954, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
    - Notes from Paris Peace Conference, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Hankey, Lord Maurice
  - Harbin., Edith Lester, Correspondence: 2 items, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Harper, Mrs. George McLean, Interview: 2 pages, undated (Box 1)
  - Harriman, Florence, Interview: 1 page, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hays, Will H.
    - Interview: 1 page, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: 3 items., 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Helm, Edith Benham (Mrs. James), Interview: 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hendrickson, G. Lincoln
    - Interviews: 1 page, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hewes, James E., Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Hewes, James E.
    See: box 1, folder 16
  - Hibben, Beth
    See: box 1, folder 48
  - Hoff, Joseph
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - Interview: 3 pages, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: 11 items, 1953, 1956, 1958-1959, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Memorandum (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hoover, James O., Interview: 1 page, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Hornbeck, S.K., Notes on Shantung (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - House, Mona
    See: box 1, folder 57
  - Howe, Margaret Flinn (Mrs. George), Interview: 1 page, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Hoyt, Margaret, Interview: 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Jones, Sir Clement
  - Jones, David B.
  - Kahler, Hugh MacNair
    - Interview; 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1945-1955 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Ms Page (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Keller, Albert Galloway, Correspondence: 5 items, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Kellogg, George Dwight
    - Interview: 1 page, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - King, Benjamin (Mr. and Mrs.)
    - Interview: 2 pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: 5 items, 1948, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - King, Wunz, Interview: 1 page, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Kirkland, Katharine Woodrow
    - Interview: 2 pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1948, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - News Clipping (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Koo, Wellington, Correspondence: 1 item, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Laroche, Jules
  - Lawrence, David
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: 5 items, 1951, 1953, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Lawton, Margaret, Correspondence: 2 items, 1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Leger, Alexis
  - Lingle, Walter L.
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Davidson College Bulletin (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - London-Paris Interviews-Misc.
    - Interview: 18 pages, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1951, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Long, Breckinridge
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Lovett, Sidney, Interview: 1 page, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - McAdoo, Eleanor Wilson, Interview: 4 pages, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - McCahill, Myles, Interview: 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - MacDonald, Francis C.
    - Interview: 2 pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - McElroy, Alice Wilson
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - McIlwain, Charles H.
  - McKoy, James H., Correspondence: 1 item, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Magie, David
  - Mahaffie, Charles
  - Mantoux, Paul, Notes on Paris Peace Conference, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mantoux, Mme. Paul
  - Massigli, René
  - Mitchell, Stewart, Correspondence: 2 items, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Moody, John, Correspondence: 2 item, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Monroe-Weinstein controversy, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 41A)
  - Nicolson, Harold
    - Interview 1 page, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence: 3 items, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Nicolson, Harold
  - Noel-Baker, Philip
  - Notestein., Wallace, Interview: 1 page, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Perry, Bliss
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence: 5 items, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Printed Material (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Portier, Capt. André
  - Princeton Interviews-Misc.
    - Interview: 8 pagew, 1949-1950, 1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Rappard, William. E., Correspondence: 2 items, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Reid, Edith Gittings
    - Interview: 1 page, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence: 3 items, 1919-1920, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Rogers, Walter S., Printed Material, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Rounesville, Hallie Alexander, Interview: 1 page, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Sayre, Francis B., Correspondence: 1 item, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Scoon, Robert, Correspondence: 2 items, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery, Correspondence 2 items, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Seymour, Charles
    - Interview: 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence: 4 items, 1949, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Shotwell Dr. James T.
    - Interview 1 page, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Ms. Page (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Skillman, Charles
  - Smith, Ira R.T., Magazine Article (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Smith, Lucy Marshall, Correspondence: 7 items, 1948, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Smith, Russell H.
  - Spring, Agnes Wright
    - Correspondence: 2 items, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Printed Material (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - St. Quentin, René de
  - Sweetser, Arthur
    - Correspondence: 4 items, 1958, 1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Notes on Paris Peace Conference,1919 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Swem, Charles, Interview 2 pages, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard
    - Correspondence: 10 items, 1951-1953, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Ms. Page (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Thompson, Huston, Interview: 2 Pages, 1949, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Three Citizens of Princeton
    See; box 1, folder 44
  - Tibbott, F.M.
  - Toynbee, Arnold, Correspondence: 2 items, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Tucker, Mona House
    - Interview: 1 page, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Turnbull, Laura S., Correspondence: 1 item, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Van Dyke, Tertius
    See: box 1, folder 46
  - Walters, Frank
  - Warren, Charles
    - Interview: 1 page, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Watt, George. W., Correspondence: 1 item, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Willert, Sir Arthur
  - Wilson, Margaret
  - Weinstein, Dr. E. A.
    See: Monroe, Robert T.
  - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Printed Description (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Wiseman, Sir William
    - Interview: 4 pages, 1952, 1954, 1957, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence: 5 items, 1951, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Memorandum and Misc. Notes (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Woodrow, Fitzwilliam McMaster
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence: 5 items, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Woodrow, James
    - Interview: 2 pages, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Correspondence: 1 item, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Webster, Charles (Sir)
  - Woodrow, Thomas R., Correspondence: 1 item, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Woolley, Robert
    - Interview: 1 page, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence: 13 items, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Misc Notes and Printed Material, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Young, Florence, Interview: 1 page, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Miscellaneous, Sketches, Genealogy, Misc. Notes (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Additional material, 1868, 1945-1946; Accession 1972-M-002; 0.25; (1 box)
  Deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1972 May
  - Black Ships Off Japan: The Story of Commodore Perry's Expedition (1946), 1868, 1945-1946
    - Typescript, with photographs and maps (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, research material, reviews (Box 1)
- Additional material, Circa 1945-1965; Accession 1973-M-001; 3 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1972 Jul 14
  - Woodrow Wilson
    - Early drafts and notes
      - Volume 1, Chapters 1-11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Volume I, Chapters 12-21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Volume II, Chapters 1-3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Volume II, Chapters 4-11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Volume II, Chapters 12-16 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Volume II, Chapters 17-21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Original setting typescript with author's & editor's annotations
      - Volume I, Chapters 1-7 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Volume I, Chapters 8-16 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Volume I, Chapters 17-19 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Volume II, Chapters 1-6 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Volume II, Chapters 7-11 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Volume II, Chapter 12-15 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Volume II, Chapter 16-22 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Page proofs, annotated
      - Volume I (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Volume II (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Volume II (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Index, original manuscript and annotated page proofs (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Page proofs, annotated (Box 3)
    - Notes on interviews, other notes and research material, correspondence and critiques, reviews (Box 3)
    - Annotated copy of Volume I, and notes for revised (1965) edition (Box 3)
    - Photostatic copy of Edith Benham Helm's TMS diary, 1937 (Box 3)
- Additional material, Circa 1960-1977; Accession 1977-M-001; 3 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1976 addition
  - America's Moment: 1918: American Diplomacy at the End of World War I (1977), Circa1960-1977
    - Early drafts and notes, and Charles Seymour's criticisms (Box 1)
    - 3rd and 4th drafts (Box 2)
    - 5th draft, revisions for 5th and 6th drafts (Box 3)
    - 6th draft (Box 4)
    - 6th draft: notes and research material (Box 5)
    - Typescript for printer, annotated (Box 5)
    - Galley proofs and page proofs, annotated (Box 5)
- Additional material, Circa 1960-1977; Accession 1978-M-001; .75 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1977 Oct
  - America's Moment: 1918: American Diplomacy at the End of World War I (1977), Circa 1960-1977
    - Typescript for printer, annotated (Box 1)
    - Galley proofs and page proofs, annotated (Box 2)
- Additional material, Circa 1957-1958; Accession 1979-M-008; (1 box)
  Deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1979 Jun 26
  - Woodrow Wilson (1958)
    - Early drafts, Circa1957-1958 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1886-1984; Accession 1984-M-008; 0.25; (1 box)
  Deposited by Arthur C. Walworth, 1981 Oct 19, 1984 Apr 24, Dec 12
  - Research materials: re Woodrow Wilson's neurological illness, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    From Accession 1982-M-008
  - Photographs of and concerning Woodrow Wilson
    - Prints, slides and negatives taken by Arthur C. Walworth, with a page of notes and a postcard, 1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Prints from originals in the National Archives, Bryn Mawr College, and other sources, 1886-1919 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Photostatic copy of part of a letter from Woodrow Wilson, signed "Your devoted brother," from original in Princeton University Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photostatic copies of sketches by Robert Lansing of Peace Conference participants, from originals in Tasker Howard Bliss Papers at Library of Congress, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Research materials re: various individuals
    - Bullitt, William C. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Interview: 3 pages, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - "Notes and reproductions from Bullitt papers before their withdrawal", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Hornbeck, Stanley K., Correspondence: 1 item, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Latourette, Kenneth S., Correspondence: 1 item, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Swope, Herbert Bayard (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Letter concerning Swope's papers at Boston University, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Warrin, Frank L., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Interviews: 4 pages, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Notes on book by E. Requin, and photostatic copies of sketches by him, 1919, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Yale, William (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Notes by Yale and Walworth, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional material, Accession 1986-M-063; 4 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - Woodrow Wilson and His Peacemakers; American Diplomacy and Paris Peace Conference: drafts and research files
    - Parts I-III (Box 1)
    - Part IV (Box 2)
    - Part V (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and index (Box 4)
- Additional material, Accession 1986-M-093; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Research materials: re Woodrow Wilson's neurological illness, 1970-1980 (Box 1)
- Additional material, Accession 1986-M-116
  Books deposited in the Arthur C. Walworth Papers, 11/5/86 and thereafter
  - Marston, F.S. The Peace Conference of 1919. New York: Oxford University Press, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard. Woodrow Wilson and World Settlement. Volume I. New York: Doubleday, Page & Company, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard. Woodrow Wilson and World Settlement. Volume II. New York: Doubleday, Page & Company, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard. Woodrow Wilson and World Settlement. Volume III. New York: Doubleday, Page & Company, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Mantoux, Paul. Les Délibérations du Conseil des Quatre (24 Mars - 28 Juin 1919). Vol.I. Paris: Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Mantoux, Paul. Les Délibérations du Conseil des Quatre (24 Mars - 28 Juin 1919). Vol. II. Paris: Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Wilson, Edith Bolling. My Memoir. New York: The Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Seymour, Charles. Letters from the Paris Peace Conference. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Palmer, Frederick. Bliss, Peacemaker: The Life and Letters of General Tasker Howard Bliss. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Seymour, Charles. The Intimate Papers of Colonel House. New York: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Bonsal, Stephen. Unfinished Business. Garden City, New York: Doubleday, Doran and Company, Inc., 1944 (Box 1)
  - Lansing, Robert. The Peace Negotiations: A Personal Narrative. New York: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1921 (Box 1)
  - Mantoux, Paul. Paris Peace Conference: 1919. trans. John Boardman Whitton. Geneve: Librairie Droz, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard. Woodrow Wilson: Life and Letters: War Leader, 1917-1918. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard. Woodrow Wilson: Life and Letters: Armistice, Mar 1-Nov 11, 1918. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Walworth, Arthur. Black Ships Off Japan. New York: Alfred A Knopf, 1946 (Box 1)
- Additional material, Accession 1987-M-018; (1 box)
  - Printer's proofs: Wilson and His Peacemakers, 1986 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1986; Accession 1988-M-020; 0.25; (1 box)
  Addition Inventory by Nancy F. Lyon 1988 January
  Received from: Arthur C. Walworth, 1987 Oct 5
  - Corrected page proofs and original drawings of the maps for Wilson and His Peacemakers, 1986 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1926-1928, 1986-1990; Accession 1988-M-070; 0.5; (1 box)
  Received from: Arthur C. Walworth, 1988
  - The Intimate Papers of Colonel House: Behind the Political Curtain, 1912-1915, annotated copy of A. C. Walworth, 1926 (Box 1)
  - The Intimate Papers of Colonel House: From Neutrality to War, 1915-1917, annotated copy of A. C. Walworth, 1926 (Box 1)
  - The Intimate Papers of Colonel House: Into the World War, annotated copy of A. C. Walworth, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Audiocassettes
    - "Luncheon with Lyndon B. Johnson," with newspaper clipping, 1987 (Box 1)
    - "Recollections of Charles Seymour", 1987 (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Wilson and His Peacemakers: American Diplomacy at the Paris Peace Conference, 1919, 1986-1990 (Box 1)
    From Accession 1990-M-052
  - Correspondence from Robin Hankey pertaining to Wilson and His Peacemakers, 1986 August 14 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1892-1949, 1976, 1979; Accession 1994-M-004; 2.50 linear feet linear feet (3 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1993 July
  Received from: Ellen R. Ebersole, 1993 Jul 13
  - Booklet containing history and pictoral description of Yale University, 1892 (Box 1)